{"tossups": [{"question": "Press coverage of a crime committed in this location was analyzed in Joan Didion's essay \"Sentimental Journeys.\" People were suspected of committing a crime in this location a\u3078\u309aer police misunderstood their references to the Tone Loc (\"tone\" loak) song \"Wild Thing.\" A full-page ad with the message \"bring back the death penalty; bring back our police!\" was prompted by a crime in this location that resulted in Raymond Kelly convening the Armstrong Commission a\u3078\u309aer Robert Morgenthau vacated the convictions of the men once thought to be responsible. A 2012 Ken Burns documentary examines a crime that occurred in this location during Ed Koch's (KOTCH's) term as mayor. In 1989, \u98dfve men of color were falsely convicted of raping a white jogger in, for 10 points, what public space in Manhattan?", "answer": "Central Park [prompt on \"New York City\" or \"NYC\" or \"Manhattan\"]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Central Park</u></b> [prompt on <u>New York City</u> or <u>NYC</u> or <u>Manhattan</u>]", "acceptable": ["Central Park"], "promptable": ["New York City", "NYC", "Manhattan"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In his sonata for this instrument, Dmitri Shostakovich subtitled the final movement adagio \"in the memory of Beethoven\" and quoted the Moonlight Sonata; that sonata for this instrument was Shostakovich's final composition. A concerto for this instrument has a version completed by the composer's son Peter, though the standard version was edited by Tibor Serly. A William Walton concerto for this instrument, dedicated \"to Christabel,\" was commissioned by Lionel Tertis. A piece for this instrument and orchestra contains a movement called \"Orgy of the Brigands\" and was written at the request of Niccolo\u0300 Paganini. The soloist in Harold in Italy plays, for 10 points, what alto-clef instrument that forms a string quartet with two violins and a cello?", "answer": "viola [accept (Shostakovich's) Viola Sonata or (Shostakovich's) Sonata for Viola and Piano or (Barto\u0301k's) Viola Concerto or (Walton's) Viola Concerto]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>viola</u></b> [accept <b><u>accept</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["viola", "accept"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "Shostakovich's"}, {"question": "The argument that this concept troublingly implies sexlessness is central to a Howard Eilberg-Schwartz monograph about a \"phallus.\" Jan Assmann's (yahn AHS-mahn's) book on the \"price of \" this concept explains its origins as a break from a cosmos-oriented paradigm. In the early 20th century, Wilhelm Schmidt argued that this concept originated from primitive non-Western cultures in an \"Ur\" form before taking on its final shape. This concept, whose adoption in Persia is central to Karl Jaspers's (YAHS-perz's) theory about the Axial Age, is central to a book arguing that it arose after a group partly composed of Midianites murdered a man who was not a Jew but instead an Egyptian of noble birth who adhered to the doctrines of Akhenaten. For 10 points, what religious concept is paired with \"Moses\" in a Sigmund Freud title?", "answer": "monotheism [accept word forms or equivalents such as the oneness of God; accept The Price of Monotheism or Ur-monotheism or Moses and Monotheism]", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>monotheism</u></b> [ accept word formsaccept <b><u>equivalents such as the oneness of God</u></b>; accept <b><u>The Price of Monotheism</u></b> or <b><u>Ur-monotheism</u></b> or <b><u>Moses and Monotheism</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["monotheism", "equivalents such as the oneness of God", "The Price of Monotheism", "Ur-monotheism", "Moses and Monotheism"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a method used in this field of science, it is common to straighten out hyperbolic curves by correcting for normal moveout. Another method used in this field of science considers a halfspace model and uses a y-axis of time minus distance over velocity to construct a reduced travel time plot. For this field's SNREI (\"sneery\") model, nonnegative integer subscripts before and after the letters \"S\" or \"T\" are used to classify normal modes, the latter being toroidal modes that correspond to SH propagation. A technique named for \"refection\" and this field uses geophones to translate velocity into voltage. The founder of this field, Andrija Mohorovic\u030cic\u0301 (moh-hoh-RAW-vih-chich), discovered the crust and mantle by observing P waves. For 10 points, what branch of geology involves the study of elastic waves produced by earthquakes?", "answer": "seismology [accept word forms such as seismological study or seismologists; accept refraction seismology or reflection seismology or seismography; prompt on \u201cgeophysics\u201d or \u201cgeodynamics\u201d or \u201cgeology\u201d before \u201cgeology\u201d]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>seismology</u></b> [accept <b><u>word forms such as seismological study</u></b> or <b><u>seismologists</u></b>; accept <b><u>refraction seismology</u></b> or <b><u>reflection seismology</u></b> or <b><u>seismography</u></b>; prompt on <u>\u201cgeophysics\u201d</u> or <u>\u201cgeodynamics\u201d</u>prompt on <u>\u201cgeology\u201d</u> before \u201cgeology\u201d]", "acceptable": ["seismology", "word forms such as seismological study", "seismologists", "refraction seismology", "reflection seismology", "seismography"], "promptable": ["\u201cgeophysics\u201d", "\u201cgeodynamics\u201d", "\u201cgeology\u201d"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In Natsume Soseki's novel Sanshiro, Professor Hirota lends an English-language book by this author to the title character, who associates the book with the professor because both are impenetrable yet interesting. W. G. Sebald's The Rings of Saturn incorporates a drawing of a pattern with \u98dfve points taken from this man's writings. Javier Mari\u0301as has translated two works by this physician and author into Spanish, including his spiritual testament on the \"Religion of a Doctor.\" He wrote that man is a \"noble animal, splendid in ashes, and pompous in the grave\" in a passage that concludes \"life is pure \u062c\u062d\u064aame, and we live by an invisible Sun within us\"; that passage by this author of The Garden of Cyrus was inspired by the discovery of a Roman burial site in Norfolk. For 10 points, name this 17th-century English writer of Hydriotaphia, also known as Urn Burial.", "answer": "Sir Thomas Browne", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Sir Thomas <b><u>Browne</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Sir Thomas Browne"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Barry Popik's research revealed that the earliest instances of a phrase pairing these two words were in Christopher Bullock's Cobbler of Preston and Edward Ward's Dancing Devils. Andreas Petersen designed a resource-denying mono-white Magic: The Gathering deck named a\u3078\u309aer these two words. A Dorothy Parker collection is named a\u3078\u309aer these two words, which are both negated in the title of a 2011 New Yorker pro\u98dfle of Peter Thiel (TEEL). A phrase pairing these two words appears in a letter to Jean-Baptiste Leroy noting that the U.S. Constitution has been established and \"has an appearance that promises permanency.\" Ben Franklin said that \"in this world nothing can be said to be certain\" except, for 10 points, what two eventualities that re\u062c\u062d\u064aect human mortality and the need for a government to fund itself?", "answer": "death and taxes [accept answers in either order; accept word forms of either answer such as dying or taxation; accept \"No Death, No Taxes\"]", "subcategory": "Other History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>death and taxes</u></b> [accept <b><u>answers in either order</u></b>; accept <b><u>word forms of either answer such as dying</u></b> or <b><u>taxation</u></b>; accept <b><u>No Death, No Taxes</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["death and taxes", "answers in either order", "word forms of either answer such as dying", "taxation", "No Death, No Taxes"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The SSC buffer used in Southern blots contains water, sodium chloride, and a salt of this compound. This compound reduces gold in the Turkevich method for making nanoparticles. In 2008, Richard Lenski discovered that E. coli spontaneously evolved the ability to metabolize this compound. This compound and ATP inhibit phospho\u00c2\u00b7fructo\u00c2\u00b7kinase. A lyase named for this compound turns it into acetyl CoA (ah-SEE-till KOH-ay) in the cytosol in the \u98dfrst step of fatty acid biosynthesis. This tricarboxylic acid is isomerized by the iron\u00c2\u2013sulfur protein aconitase (ah-KON-ih-tace) and is formed by a Claisen (CLY-zen) condensation from oxaloacetate (ox-AL-oh-ASS-eh-tate) right a\u3078\u309aer pyruvate oxidation; then, in a pathway that occurs in the mitochondrial matrix, it's oxidized to an F\u00c2\u00b7A\u00c2\u00b7D\u00c2\u00b7H2, two N\u00c2\u00b7A\u00c2\u00b7D\u00c2\u00b7H, two CO2, and another oxaloacetate. For 10 points, what organic acid sometimes names the Krebs cycle?", "answer": "citric acid [or sodium citrate; accept citric acid cycle]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>citric acid</u></b> [or <b><u>sodium citrate</u></b>; accept <b><u>citric acid cycle</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["citric acid", "sodium citrate", "citric acid cycle"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This book argues that nonsense shouldn't be understood as gibberish but rather as something that lies beyond the limits of sense. This book states that philosophy is not a natural science but instead is an activity that clari\u98dfes thoughts and can set limits to disputations in natural science. The introduction to this book was written by Bertrand Russell, who wrote the article \"The Philosophy of Logical Atomism\" a\u3078\u309aer reading it. This book posits that facts are pictures and that language is used to make those pictures. This book is presented in a series of declarative statements that are hierarchically numbered based on their relation to its seven main propositions. The proposition \"the world is everything that is the case\" appears in, for 10 points, what early text by Ludwig Wittgenstein (VITT-gen-shtyne)?", "answer": "Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus [prompt on \"the Tractatus\" or \"TLP\"]", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus</u></b> [prompt on the <u>Tractatus</u> or <u>TLP</u>]", "acceptable": ["Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus"], "promptable": ["Tractatus", "TLP"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Members of this family title a Peter Ackroyd novel in which the bookseller William Ireland presents them with a lost Shakespeare play called Vortigern. Kathy Watson wrote a biography of a woman from this family called The Devil Kissed Her, which describes how that woman stabbed her paralyzed mother to death with a carving knife. In an essay by a man from this family, Ho-ti leaves his cottage in the care of his son Bo-bo, who sets the cottage on \u98dfre and inadvertently learns how good pork tastes; that member of this family included \"Old China\" and \"A Dissertation upon Roast Pig\" in his collection Essays of Elia. The children's adaptations found in 1807's Tales from Shakespeare were by members of, for 10 points, what family of London writers including Mary and her brother Charles?", "answer": "Lamb family [accept the Lambs or Charles Lamb or Mary Lamb or The Lambs of London]", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Lamb family</u></b> [accept the <b><u>Lambs</u></b> or <b><u>Charles Lamb</u></b> or <b><u>Mary Lamb</u></b> or <b><u>The Lambs of London</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Lamb family", "Lambs", "Charles Lamb", "Mary Lamb", "The Lambs of London"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This reaction is done in DCM to ring-expand a dioxane in the last step of Avery's artemisinin (ar-teh-MIS-in-in) synthesis. The Baeyer\u00c2\u2013Villiger (\"buyer\"-FIH-lih-ger) intermediate is named for its similarity to this reaction's intermediate, a zwitterionic carbonyl oxide. This reaction is worked up reductively using zinc and acetic acid or oxidatively with H2O2. It occurs by a 1,3 (one three) dipolar cycloaddition and subsequent retro-dipolar cycloaddition to break a \u98dfve-member ring according to Criegee's (KREE-gay's) mechanism. Diurea (\"die\"-yur-EE-ah) is added to poly\u00c2\u00b7buta\u00c2\u00b7diene and rubber to prevent them from undergoing this reaction. Potassium permanganate does the same thing as this reaction, except that it oxidizes monosubstituted carbons past aldehydes to carboxylic acids. For 10 points, in what reaction does a triatomic allotrope of oxygen cleave double bonds?", "answer": "ozonolysis [or ozone cleavage; or ozone cracking; prompt on alkene cleavage; prompt on ozone by itself until \"cleavage\" is read, then accept it a\u3078\u309aerwards]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>ozonolysis</u></b> [or <b><u>ozone cleavage</u></b>; or <b><u>ozone cracking</u></b>; prompt on <u>alkene cleavage</u>; prompt on <u>ozone by itself until \"cleavage\" is read, then accept it a\u3078\u309aerwards</u>]", "acceptable": ["ozonolysis", "ozone cleavage", "ozone cracking"], "promptable": ["alkene cleavage", "ozone by itself until \"cleavage\" is read, then accept it a\u3078\u309aerwards"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A speech given a\u3078\u309aer this event claimed that its victim \"represented the living, the eternal truths, reminding us of the right path, drawing us from error.\" The perpetrator of this action was forced to wear a nose ring as a child because his superstitious parents feared having a son. The victim of this event had criticized a pogrom perpetrated during \"Direct Action Day,\" part of a violent period called the \"Week of the Long Knives.\" Henri Cartier-Bresson documented the public mourning a\u3078\u309aer this event, which was perpetrated by radicals associated with the RSS and Hindu Mahasabha. A speech beginning \"the light has gone out of our lives\" mourned the victim of this event, who was shot by Nathuram Godse. For 10 points, what 1948 event claimed the life of a nonviolent Indian activist?", "answer": "assassination of Mahatma Gandhi [or assassination of Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi; or assassination of the Mahatma; or assassination of Bapu; accept answers mentioning Gandhi or Mahatma and an indication of his killing or murder or shooting or similar]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>assassination of Mahatma Gandhi</u></b> [or <b><u>assassination of Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi</u></b>; or <b><u>assassination of the Mahatma</u></b>; or <b><u>assassination of Bapu</u></b>; accept <b><u>answers mentioning Gandhi</u></b> or <b><u>Mahatma and an indication of his killing</u></b> or <b><u>murder</u></b> or <b><u>shooting</u></b> or <b><u>similar</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["assassination of Mahatma Gandhi", "assassination of Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi", "assassination of the Mahatma", "assassination of Bapu", "answers mentioning Gandhi", "Mahatma and an indication of his killing", "murder", "shooting", "similar"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "[missing]", "answer": "[missing]", "answer_formatted": "<b><u></u></b> [missing]", "acceptable": [""], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man urged other architects to abandon prepackaged styles that imitate past architecture and embrace science and industry in his address \"The Art and Cra\u3078\u309a of the Machine.\" William Storrer catalogued the works of this architect, which include a personal home featuring a hexagonal \"cabaret theater\" room built from concrete and stone to enhance its acoustics. He worked with his students Kaneji Domoto and Aaron Resnick on a planned community, known as a \"historic district,\" in Westchester County, New York. He mistakenly attributed to Samuel Butler a term that he used to describe a building built for Herbert and Katherine Jacobs in Madison, Wisconsin. The Usonian style was championed by, for 10 points, what American architect who designed houses called Taliesin (tall-ee-AY-sin) and Fallingwater?", "answer": "Frank Lloyd Wright [or Frank Lincoln Wright]", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Frank Lloyd Wright</u></b> [or <b><u>Frank Lincoln Wright</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Frank Lloyd Wright", "Frank Lincoln Wright"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This poet described \"Saint Christopher, naked\" and \"full of celestial tongues\" asking a \"child / playing a sweet distracted bagpipe\" if he can li\u3078\u309a up her dress to see her naked body. Another poem by this man contains the refrain \"green, how I want you green.\" This poet of \"Preciosa and the Breeze\" and \"Ballad of the Sleepwalker\" wrote of a \"fat lady\" who is the \"moon's antagonist\" in the poem \"Landscape of a Vomiting Multitude,\" which describes a scene on Coney Island. The phrases \"I will not see it\" and \"at \u98dfve o'clock in the a\u3078\u309aernoon\" are repeated in a poem by this author that was inspired by the death of Ignacio Sa\u0301nchez Meji\u0301as (may-HEE-ahs). Gypsy Ballads and Poet in New York are collections by, for 10 points, what Spanish author of \"Lament for the Death of a Bull\u98dfghter\" and the play Blood Wedding?", "answer": "Federico Garci\u0301a Lorca [accept either underlined portion; or Federico del Sagrado Corazo\u0301n de Jesu\u0301s Garci\u0301a Lorca (accept either underlined portion)]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Federico Garci\u0301a <b><u>Lorca</u></b> [accept <b><u>either underlined portion</u></b>; or <b><u>Federico del Sagrado Corazo\u0301n de Jesu\u0301s Garci\u0301a Lorca</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Federico Garci\u0301a Lorca", "either underlined portion", "Federico del Sagrado Corazo\u0301n de Jesu\u0301s Garci\u0301a Lorca"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept either underlined portion"}, {"question": "After this war had already been concluded, a disgruntled commander plundered church lands near Bury St. Edmunds, where he choked to death on his meal. The Peterborough Chronicle states that, during this confliict, \"men said openly that Christ and his saints slept.\" After Robert of Gloucester was captured in this war's Rout of Winchester, he was exchanged for a king who had been imprisoned since losing the Battle of Lincoln. The leader of one side in this war escaped from Oxford Castle by wearing white and crossing a frozen moat during a snowstorm. The Treaty of Wallingford ended this war, which began after the death of William Adelin on the White Ship. For 10 points, what English civil war between Empress Matilda and Stephen of Blois was named for its lawless nature?", "answer": "The Anarchy [do not accept or prompt on \"English Civil War\" or similar answers]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Anarchy</u></b> [do not accept or prompt on \"English Civil War\" or \"similar answers\"]", "acceptable": ["The Anarchy"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": ["English Civil War", "similar answers"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An investigative journalist in this country uncovered both the AKH scandal, involving wasted funds for a hospital in its capital, and the Noricum affair, in which arms were sold illegally to Iran. This country gave in to the demands of the Palestinian terrorist group As-Sa'iqa (ahs-sah-EE-kah) by closing the Scho\u0308nau (\"SHOE-now\") transit center. With Paul McCartney, a politician from this country organized a series of concerts for the relief of Cambodian war victims. This country's far-right Freedom Party was led by Jo\u0308rg Haider (yerg \"HI\"-der). A politician from this country, who was accused of lying about his involvement in Nazi war crimes, succeeded U Thant (oo tant) as U.N. secretary-general. Kurt Waldheim (VAHLD-hyme) was from, for 10 points, what country that was handed over to Nazi Germany by Arthur Seyss-Inquart (ZICE INK-vahrt) in the Anschluss?", "answer": "Republic of Austria [or Republik O\u0308sterreich]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "Republic of <b><u>Austria</u></b> [or <b><u>Republik O\u0308sterreich</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Republic of Austria", "Republik O\u0308sterreich"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This artist was inspired by Thomas Percy's translation of the Northern Antiquities to paint a work in which a man cowers in fear in the prow of a boat as a naked god pulls at a monster with a chain. This artist was saved from \u98dfnancial ruin by his principal patron, Thomas Coutts, a\u3078\u309aer the public failure of a venture inspired by this artist's participation in John Boydell's Shakespeare Gallery. This artist, the driving force behind the Milton Gallery, painted Thor Battering the Midgard Serpent and a work in which a small table contains a book, a mirror, and a vial; in that work by this artist, a white-eyed horse pokes its head from behind a curtain while an incubus sits on the chest of a sleeping woman. For 10 points, identify this Anglo-Swiss artist who painted The Nightmare.", "answer": "Henry Fuseli (FOO-sell-ee) [or Johann Heinrich Fu\u0308ssli]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Henry <b><u>Fuseli</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Henry Fuseli"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "FOO-sell-ee"}, {"question": "In two dimensions, the x and y components of this quantity are set equal to partial derivatives of the stream function, such that the de\u98dfnitions satisfy the Cauchy\u00c2\u2013Riemann equations. A partial derivative with respect to time plus \"this quantity dot the gradient\" de\u98dfnes a type of derivative that, depending on the source, is described as \"total,\" \"substantial,\" or \"material.\" A streamline is de\u98dfned as being parallel to the components of this quantity's \u98dfeld, whose line integral around a closed curve de\u98dfnes the circulation. The mass \u062c\u062d\u064aux is de\u98dfned as density times this quantity's vector \u98dfeld. Setting the partial time derivative, divergence, or curl of this quantity equal to zero de\u98dfnes, respectively, \"steady,\" \"incompressible,\" and \"irrotational\" \u062c\u062d\u064aows. For 10 points, what quantity's derivative yields a \u062c\u062d\u064auid's acceleration?", "answer": "]ow velocity [accept u or v\u062c\u062d\u064a uid\u062c\u062d\u064a", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>]ow velocity</u></b>", "acceptable": ["]ow velocity"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This phrase, which provides the subtitle of a 1926 Basil Mathews book about a religion \"on trek,\" was the title of the \u98dfnal section of a 1990 Bernard Lewis essay in The Atlantic titled for the \"roots\" of a particular \"rage.\" Hans Ko\u0308chler coined a similar phrase to this one, except with \"dialogue\" as the \u98dfrst word. An essay published in Foreign Affairs that identi\u98dfed a \"fault line\" running through the former Yugoslavia was titled for this phrase followed by a question mark. This phrase titles an essay and book, published in response to Francis Fukuyama's The End of History and the Last Man, that predict the rise of global con\u062c\u062d\u064aicts based on cultural divisions. For 10 points, what phrase titles a book on the \"remaking of world order\" by Samuel Huntington?", "answer": "(the) clash of civilizations [accept \"The Clash of Civilizations?\" or The Clash of Civilizations and the Remaking of World Order or Young Islam on Trek: A Study in the Clash of Civilizations]", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u></u></b>", "acceptable": [""], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "the"}, {"question": "In a 1979 play, a character with this profession laughs at her own joke a\u3078\u309aer asking \"Doctor Livingstone, I presume?\"; in that John Pielmeier play, the psychiatrist Martha Livingstone evaluates Agnes, a woman in this profession who has been accused of murdering her newborn baby. Before going to take a nap, a character in this profession instructs a seven-year-old named Thomas to wield a gun against Aloysius (al-oo-ISH-us), who needs to use the bathroom; that woman in this profession kills her former pupil Gary Sullivan for being gay and \"explains it all for you\" in a Christopher Durang play. In a play by John Patrick Shanley, a member of this profession suspects that Donald Muller is the victim of Father Flynn's abuse. Aloysius Beauvier from the play Doubt holds, for 10 points, what job also held by Sister Mary Ignatius?", "answer": "nuns [accept sisters before \"Sister\"; do not accept or prompt on \"priests\" or similar answers]", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>nuns</u></b> [accept <b><u>sisters</u></b> before \"Sister; do not accept or prompt on \"priests\" or \"similar answers\"]", "acceptable": ["nuns", "sisters"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": ["priests", "similar answers"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A hidden message warning of this king's activities was discovered when the Spartans, on the suggestion of their queen, scraped away the wax from a pair of blank writing tablets. This man had the eldest son of Pythius sawn in half a\u3078\u309aer Pythius interpreted an eclipse as a bad omen. While in exile, Demaratus (deh-mah-RAT-us) fought for this king, who once paused a march to admire a plane tree that he cloaked in golden jewelry. A bribe convinced Eurybiades (yu-ree-BY-ah-dees) to \u98dfght this man's navy at Artemisium (ar-teh-MISS-ee-um); that navy was later defeated by Themistocles while this king watched from a throne on Mount Aigaleo (\"eye\"-gah-LAY-oh). This king built pontoon bridges across the Hellespont during a campaign in which his forces lost the Battle of Salamis (SAL-uh-miss). For 10 points, name this king of Persia who defeated Leonidas at Thermopylae (ther-MAH-poh-lie) during his invasion of Greece.", "answer": "Xerxes I [or Xerxes the Great; prompt on \"Xerxes\"]", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Xerxes I</u></b> [or <b><u>Xerxes the Great</u></b>; prompt on <u>Xerxes</u>]", "acceptable": ["Xerxes I", "Xerxes the Great"], "promptable": ["Xerxes"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}